<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Stitched.eth</title>
    <link href="https://stitchedeth.github.io/ens/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://stitchedeth.github.io/ens" />
    <updated>2022-09-21T23:15:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>CoreDevs</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://stitchedeth.github.io/ens</id>

    <entry>
        <title>About</title>
        <author>
            <name>CoreDevs</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://stitchedeth.github.io/ens/about/"/>
        <id>https://stitchedeth.github.io/ens/about/</id>

        <updated>2022-09-21T23:05:00-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://stitchedeth.github.io/ens/media/posts/18/Wide-Catalog-10.jpg" alt="" />
                    Learn more about how the stitched.eth ecosystem brings real-world utility to NFTs by embedding them with legally-enforceable intellectual property - worldwide, exclusive copyright interests What is the stitched.eth project all about? What problems does this solve? What stitched.eth does for Artists What stitched.eth does for&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://stitchedeth.github.io/ens/media/posts/18/Wide-Catalog-10.jpg" alt="" />
                <div class="subtitle">
<h6 class="align-center"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Learn more about how the <em>stitched.eth</em> ecosystem brings real-world utility to NFTs by embedding them with legally-enforceable intellectual property - worldwide, <em>exclusive</em> copyright interests</span></h6>
</div>
<ul>
<li>
<h5 style="margin-top: 3.5vh;"><a href="#project-overview">What is the <i>stitched.eth</i> project all about?</a></h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5 style="margin-top: 3.5vh;"><a href="#problems-solved">What problems does this solve?</a></h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5 style="margin-top: 3.5vh;"><a href="../../../../../../adore#artists">What <i>stitched.eth</i> does for Artists</a></h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5 style="margin-top: 3.5vh;"><a href="../../../../../../adore#patrons">What <i>stitched.eth</i> does for Collectors &amp; Patrons</a></h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5 style="margin-top: 3.5vh;"><a href="../../../../../../adore#industry">What <i>stitched.eth</i> does for Clothing Manufacturers</a></h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5 style="margin-top: 3.5vh;"><a href="../../../../../../adore#consumers">What <i>stitched.eth</i> does for everyone</a></h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5 style="margin-top: 3.5vh;"><a href="#new-artists">How artists are chosen</a></h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5 style="margin-top: 3.5vh;"><a href="#copyright-license">What copyright does the artist give to <i>stitched.eth</i>?</a></h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5 style="margin-top: 3.5vh;"><a href="#exclusive-copyright">What makes exclusive copyright interests special?</a></h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5 style="margin-top: 3.5vh;"><a href="#just-visual-art">Just visual art?</a></h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5 style="margin-top: 3.5vh;"><a href="#get-NFTs">How to acquire the copyright-embedded "Design NFT"</a></h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5 style="margin-top: 3.5vh;"><a href="#produce-clothes">How to produce clothes</a></h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5 style="margin-top: 3.5vh;"><a href="#buy-clothes">How to buy the clothes?</a></h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5 style="margin-top: 3.5vh;"><a href="#degen">I’m a degen. How do I make money from this?</a></h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5 style="margin-top: 3.5vh;"><a href="#design-NFT">What is a "Design NFT"</a></h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5 style="margin-top: 3.5vh;"><a href="#authentication">How does <i>stitched.eth</i> ensure that the art is limited edition and legitimate?</a></h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5 style="margin-top: 3.5vh;"><a href="#money">Where does the money go?</a></h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5 style="margin-top: 3.5vh;"><a href="#details">How does it all work?</a></h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5 style="margin-top: 3.5vh;"><a href="#NFT">What blockchain do you use for the NFTs?</a></h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5 style="margin-top: 3.5vh;"><a href="#contact">How can I contact the team?</a></h5>
</li>
</ul>
<h2><strong><a id="project-overview"></a>What is the <i>stitched.eth</i> project all about?</strong></h2>
<p><em>stitched.eth</em> is bringing real-world utility to the blockchain by embedding exclusive, legally-enforceable intellectual property interests (specifically, exclusive copyright interests) into NFTs (we call these “Design NFTs”) and creating an ecosystem wherein anyone with a crypto wallet can trustlessly trade in this real-world property and even use their copyright - not just sit on it - by manufacturing physical clothing and art with blockchain provenance, thereby creating limited-edition collectible fashions from real-world artists that may or may not be otherwise participating in the blockchain world.</p>
<p><em>stitched.eth</em> makes it easy for anyone to trade in copyright interests trustlessly on the blockchain. You don’t have to hire a lawyer or negotiate directly with the artist. You just use your crypto wallet to buy the Design NFT. It’s that easy. And it’s almost that easy to get the art out there in the world.</p>
<p>Once you have the Design NFT, you can use our ecosystem to communicate with the artist to get the art produced for your collection. Or you can even request that the artist have the clothes produced themselves. Now that the art you have an exclusive license for is actually on the clothes, you just need to get those clothes out to the masses. That’s made much easier to do because our ecosystem ensures your customers, and the artist’s collectors, that the art is legitimate and limited edition, collectible pieces. You don’t have to do that at all. It’s all on the blockchain. So now you have a financial incentive to invest in manufacturing the art and promoting it because you can sell the pieces to real collectors and capitalize on any appreciation of the copyright interest.</p>
<h2><strong><a id="problems-solved"></a>What problems does this solve?</strong></h2>
<p>The <em>stitched.eth</em> ecosystem solves problems for <a href="../../../../../../adore#artists">artists</a>, <a href="../../../../../../adore#patrons">collectors</a>, <a href="../../../../../../adore#industry">clothing manufacturers</a> and <a href="../../../../../../adore#consumers">everyone who wears clothes</a>. Click on the links to learn more about the problems that we're solving for each group.</p>
<h2><strong><a id="new-artists"></a>How artists are chosen</strong></h2>
<p>Artists can apply to join the <em>stitched.eth </em>ecosystem by submitting an application or by contacting the dev team on <a href="https://www.instagram.com/stitched.eth/" rel="nofollow">instagram</a> or <a href="https://twitter.com/stitchedeth" rel="nofollow">twitter</a>. <em>stitched.eth </em>screens the artists and invites approved artists to create clothing samples. Photographers then shoot the samples, share the samples on social media, and the <em>stitched.eth </em>community can vote their $THREAD tokens on what artists and samples get included in the ecosystem (more info on this below). The<em> stitched.eth</em> community can also independently recommend and vote on artists and specific artwork.</p>
<p>The <em>stitched.eth </em>community will determine what artists get invited to join through a decentralized voting process, open to all token-holders. The <em>stitched.eth</em> token is called $THREAD and lives on the Polygon Matic network at contract address <a href="https://polygonscan.com/address/0x64138094afae67c9796e2c9d250c977e3d813573">0x64138094AFAe67c9796E2C9d250C977e3D813573</a>. $THREAD holders vote in proportion to the number of tokens they hold. <em>stitched.eth </em>airdrops $THREAD tokens to its community based on investment, usage and participation in IRL events. $THREAD is also available for trading on decentralized AMM exchanges including Quickswap and Uniswap. </p>
<p>If you would like to join us an artist, please reach out to our core devs on instagram and twitter and we can give you more details. We want to work with all kinds of artists, especially those who have interesting ideas about how to use apparel in their practice. Keep in mind that you will have to work directly with the Design NFT holders to produce the garments and that you will be responsible for making sure garments are delivered to the design NFT holders along with garment NFTs. Make sure you take a few minutes to read more about how all of this works on this website.</p>
<h2><strong><a id="copyright-license"></a>What copyright does the artist give to stitched.eth?</strong></h2>
<p>For each artwork that artists wish to make part of the <em>stitched.eth</em> ecosystem, artists assign their copyright in that artwork to <em>stitched.eth</em> (via a wet-signed contract) but the artists reserve their rights (1) to use the design on any medium other than clothing, (2) to refuse to produce the design for any particular licensee/NFT-holder, and (3) to use any other designs on apparel that haven't been licensed to <em>stitched.eth</em>. </p>
<p><em>stitched.eth</em> then creates derivative works of the artwork for clothing to embed into Design NFTs so that each Design NFT has its own exclusive copyright. By embedding the rights that stitched.eth received from the artist originally, the copyright has the same limitations, and <em>stitched.eth</em> adds a yearly usage allocation restriction - each year there is a maximum number of reproductions that the Design NFT holder can use, but those yearly usage allocations add up over time if they are not used.</p>
<p>Per the terms of the <em>stitched.eth </em>license agreement, the artist can say "no" to any particular design request, but the artist also cannot make any reproductions of the artwork on clothing without the approval of the corresponding Design NFT holder. Of course, the artist can make reproductions on items other than clothing. </p>
<p>The Design NFT holder must negotiate directly with the artist to manufacture garments featuring their artwork. That process does not involve <em>stitched.eth</em> except that we provide the technology to ensure that the artist is communicating with the true Design NFT holder. </p>
<p>In the event that the artist and the Design NFT holder cannot agree on a reproduction run, then the yearly allocation goes unused, continues to accumulate with the Design NFT, and the Design NFT holder may choose to retain the Design NFT or sell it to someone else who can then use the allocation.</p>
<h2><strong><a id="exclusive-copyright"></a>What makes exclusive copyright interests special?</strong></h2>
<p>You get the right to sue for copyright infringement only if you own an exclusive copyright. BAYC owners can’t sue for infringement on their own accord because they own only a nonexclusive license.</p>
<h2><strong><a id="just-visual-art"></a>Just visual art?</strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">No, not just visual art.  This is also a great ecosystem for poets and other types of artists that might be hard to “collect” in the traditional sense. It’s also a great ecosystem for artists who want to expose more people to their message than a small collector base. </span></p>
<h2><strong><a id="get-NFTs"></a>How to acquire the copyright-embedded "Design NFT"</strong></h2>
<p>Anyone can buy our copyright-embedded Design NFT. We recommend that you use  the official links found here on our website to make sure you're getting authentic Design NFTs. </p>
<h2><a id="produce-clothes"></a>How to produce clothes</h2>
<p>First, you'll need to buy one or more Design NFTs. Each Design NFT is embedded with an exclusive license to create a fixed number of garments per year featuring the artwork of the Design NFT. </p>
<p>The terms of the license are available to review in the metadata of the Design NFT. You should review the license terms before you purchase the NFT, and if you plan on producing clothes, it would probably be a good idea to reach out to the artist before you purchase the NFT to make sure that they are going to be on board with your planned use. You can even negotiate your contract with the artist before purchasing the NFT. But if the Design NFT is sold before you're able to buy it, you may not be able to purchase it at a later date - whoever purchases the Design NFT will control it until they transfer the ownership of it. </p>
<p>All of the Design NFTs come embedded with an exclusive copyright license, but the license requires you to obtain artist approval before the artwork is reproduced. You should expect that the artist is going to want to be paid a royalty or fixed fee of some kind. If the artist does not approve of your use, or you are not able to work out a deal, then the terms of the license prevent you from reproducing the artwork. However, you still own the exclusive rights to the artwork, so the artist is also not allowed to reproduce it, and you can either continue to hold the NFT or sell it on any NFT exchange platform that you wish. </p>
<p>You can request that the artist apply the art to fabric, or you can work out a deal to apply the art yourself (so long as it's approved by the artist). Some of the artists may be able to produce clothing themselves or have contacts with manufacturers to be able to get a collection produced for you if you so choose.</p>
<p>As soon as the artwork is applied to a garment, it is important to register that with <em>stitched.eth</em> so that we can record that use. </p>
<h2><a id="buy-clothes"></a>How to buy the clothes?</h2>
<p>If you want to collect the garments themselves, you'll need to buy them from a retailer! Check out our <a href="https://www.instagram.com/stitched.eth/" rel="nofollow">instagram</a> or <a href="https://twitter.com/stitchedeth" rel="nofollow">twitter</a> to find some retailers, or you can consider becoming your own retailer by purchasing a Design NFT. </p>
<h2><a id="degen"></a>I’m a degen. How do I make money from this?</h2>
<p>It’s okay, we like money too. In the <em>stitched.eth</em> ecosystem, there is value everywhere. When you own a Design NFT with the copyright embedded into it, you are getting a legally-enforceable, exclusive copyright interest. This means that clothes featuring the art featured in your Design NFT will not get produced except through you. So if there is value in the art or the artist, then there will be a demand for the products you have the exclusive right to control.</p>
<p>These are not regular tokens. This isn’t a ponzi scheme and doesn’t require liquidity to be locked up. You are getting real-world intellectual property, the value of which is determined by the value of the art itself.</p>
<p>You can either buy the Design NFT and do nothing and hope the value appreciates and resell it; or you can buy the Design NFT to make clothes and sell the clothes.</p>
<p>We think our Design NFT holders will get the most out of ownership by actually producing the clothes - that’s because (1) your artist gets more famous from all the people walking around asking your customers who the artist is that they’re wearing, (2) you can make immediately money from selling the clothes without selling your art, (3) your specific Design NFT gets more and more famous, and (4) you might then be able to benefit from additional appreciation if you choose to sell the Design NFT at a later date.</p>
<h2><a id="design-NFT"></a>What is a "Design NFT"</h2>
<p>A Design NFT is an NFT (non-fungible token) in the stitched.eth ecosystem that we have embedded with an <span style="font-weight: 400;">exclusive, legally-enforceable</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> copyright interests. Anyone with a crypto wallet can trustlessly trade in this real-world property and even use their copyright - not just sit on it - by manufacturing physical clothing and art with blockchain provenance, thereby creating limited-edition collectible fashions from real-world artists that may or may not be otherwise participating in the blockchain world. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">All artists in the <em>stitched.eth </em>ecosystem assign <em>stitched.eth</em> the copyright in specific artwork via a traditional wet-signed contract. <em>stitched.eth</em> then creates variations of the original (called “derivative works”) to be applied to clothing, each with its own copyright. Then <em>stitched.eth</em> signs an exclusive license agreement for each derivative work that grants the holder of the Design NFT featuring the derivative the exclusive right to reproduce the work with some limitations - for instance, as discussed above, the artist has to approve all uses, and there is an annual quantity limitation. Each of these contracts are part of the Design NFT metadata, along with the URL tracking the allocations available (and already having been used) at any given time, and a digital file of the artwork. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Design NFT holder also gets access to our communication channels where we have limited access to only the artist and the NFT holder. That way the artist knows they are communicating with the real NFT holder when an order is placed. The Design NFT holder can then work out a deal directly with the artist and pay the artist directly. </span></p>
<h2><a id="authentication"></a>How does <i>stitched.eth</i> ensure that the art is limited edition and legitimate?</h2>
<p><em>stitched.eth</em> builds some limitations into the exclusive copyright license. Specifically, (1) a fixed number of units available for production per year - this number is particular to each Design NFT and found in the metadata of the Design NFT itself and (2) a requirement that the artist approve all uses of the art - so while you may own the exclusive right to reproduce the art on clothing, the artist can say no to any particular use (accordingly, you probably want to negotiate with the artist before buying the Design NFT if you plan on manufacturing clothes).</p>
<p>Once the artist produces the artwork to the manufacturer's spec as the manufacturer and the artist have agreed upon, the artist will notify <em>stitched.eth </em>(or if the manufacturer is producing the art, then the manufacturer will do the notification), and <em>stitched.eth </em>will note that the yearly “allocation” for that Design NFT is diminished by the number of units that were produced.</p>
<p>The allocations for each copyright-embedded Design NFT are listed on unique pages of our .eth domain. Each page will record all allocations that are used and outstanding and how many allocations have accrued to date. That way, everyone can inspect this public record, which all potential Design NFT purchasers should do prior to purchase so that you know how many allocations the Design NFT has left for this year.</p>
<p><em>stitched.eth</em> also offers manufacturers the ability to create NFTs for each garment (that do not have copyright interests embedded in them; we call these “Garment NFTs”) for listing on the webpage for that specific Design NFT. That way, when the manufacturer sells the clothing, they can transfer the Garment NFT along with it, and the collector can then ensure that they are getting authentic product and the public can track the number of authentic products out there.</p>
<h2><a id="money"></a>Where does the money go?</h2>
<p>Design NFT holders are required by the terms of their copyright license to order their allocations of physical garments directly through the artist or otherwise obtain artist approval. This means that the artist and the collector have to negotiate directly, and the money flows from the collector directly to the artist. <i>stitched.eth</i> does not take a cut of any money paid to the artist for the allocations.</p>
<p>Accordingly, since the agreement for the physical garments is made directly between the artist and the collector, the artist has an obligation to deliver the goods according to the terms of that agreement.</p>
<p>The only source of revenue for <i>stitched.eth</i> is from the initial sale of each NFT in the series and a percentage of each subsequent resale of the Design NFT. </p>
<h2><strong><a id="details"></a>How does it all work?</strong></h2>
<p>It all begins with the artist. </p>
<p>An artist creates an iconic design or work that can be translated onto apparel. That might be a stencil, a graphic image for screen printing, an applique ...or whatever else the artist can imagine.</p>
<p>The artist assigns the copyright in this design to <em>stitched.eth. </em>The copyright assignment reserves the artist the rights to use the design on any application other than apparel. By virtue of doing this, the artist does transfer the right to reproduce that artwork on any other clothing, but the artist maintains the rights (1) to use the artwork on any other medium, (2) to refuse to produce the artwork for any particular licensee, and (3) to use any other artwork on apparel that haven't also been licensed. </p>
<p>"Artwork" in this case means any "work of art" as defined by copyright law - so it includes any kind of art, from visual art to poetry. </p>
<p><em>stitched.eth</em> then creates a series of derivative works and exclusively licenses each of those derivative-work copyrights into ERC-721 NFTs by embedding the pdf of a wet-signed exclusive license agreement for each derivative into the metadata of an NFT - each of those NFTs is a Design NFT. A pdf of the copyright assignment from the artist to <em>stitched.eth</em> is also embedded into the NFT metadata of each Design NFT. The exclusive license agreement specifically references each of the derivative works and prevents <em>stitched.eth</em> from making any further derivatives. </p>
<p>The Design NFTs are then minted and made available for sale. At that time, no one else in the world can reproduce the specific artwork on clothing except for the holders of those minted NFTs.</p>
<p>The exclusive license restricts the Design NFT-holder's reproduction rights by: (1) limiting the number of reproductions per year - the exact number of which is specified in the contract - except that the number of reproductions can accumulate over the years (these are the artwork "allocations") and (2) requiring the artist to approve any and all reproductions of the artwork. </p>
<p>Accordingly, the artist can say "no" to any particular production request of the Design NFT-holder, but the artist also cannot reproduce of the artwork without the approval of the Design NFT holder.</p>
<p>The Design NFT holder negotiates directly with the artist to get approval for manufacturing garments. <em>stitched.eth</em> provides the platform for communication with and access to the artist, but <em>stitched.eth</em> plays no role in those negotiations and is not entitled to any royalties from the manufacture or sale of the garments.</p>
<p>In the event that the artist and the Design NFT holder cannot agree on a reproduction run, then the yearly allocation will continue to accumulate with the Design NFT, and the Design NFT holder may choose to retain the Design NFT or sell it to someone else who can then use the allocation. </p>
<p>Whenever the artwork is used on a garment, <em>stitched.eth</em> registers each reproduction on a page on this website that is dedicated to the particular Design NFT (the location of which is embedded in its metadata). The manufacturer can mint (or pay <em>stitched.eth</em> to mint) Garment NFTs that can be used to authenticate each garment and <em>stitched.eth</em> will register those Garment NFTs on the same webpage. The manufacturer can then transfer the NFT to the crypto wallet of the purchaser of the garment. The metadata of the Garment NFT should include, at least, an image of the garment, the name of the Design NFT artwork, and any other identifying information from the manufacturer.</p>
<p>If a Garment NFT is minted and registered on the <em>stitched.eth</em> website and the garment is conferred together with the Garment NFT, the garment can be authenticated simply by proving that the owner has the corresponding NFT in their wallet. </p>
<p>All of the updates are hashed on IPFS, so even if every core dev dies off in a plane crash, the IPFS hash will remain for anyone else to take over the project or confirm a garment's authenticity. </p>
<h2><strong><a id="NFT"></a>What blockchain do you use for the NFTs?</strong></h2>
<p>We use two different blockchains for the NFTs.</p>
<p>The Design NFTs with embedded copyrights are built on the ethereum blockchain.</p>
<p>The Garment NFTs that <em>stitched.eth</em> mints built on the Stacks blockchain. However, manufacturers are free to use any other blockchain. Regardless of what blockchain is used, the Garment NFT addresses will be listed on this website.</p>
<h2><strong><a id="contact"></a>How can I contact the team?</strong></h2>
<p>Join our community on Discord and chat with us. The <em>stitched.eth</em> core team is online all the time, happy to help you out with any question!</p>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Blue Candy Skull</title>
        <author>
            <name>CoreDevs</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://stitchedeth.github.io/ens/blue-candy-skull/"/>
        <id>https://stitchedeth.github.io/ens/blue-candy-skull/</id>

        <updated>2022-09-19T20:30:49-05:00</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://stitchedeth.github.io/ens/media/posts/16/Candy-Skull-original.jpg" sizes="100vw" srcset="https://stitchedeth.github.io/ens/media/posts/16/responsive/Candy-Skull-original-xs.jpg 300w ,https://stitchedeth.github.io/ens/media/posts/16/responsive/Candy-Skull-original-sm.jpg 480w ,https://stitchedeth.github.io/ens/media/posts/16/responsive/Candy-Skull-original-md.jpg 768w ,https://stitchedeth.github.io/ens/media/posts/16/responsive/Candy-Skull-original-lg.jpg 1024w ,https://stitchedeth.github.io/ens/media/posts/16/responsive/Candy-Skull-original-xl.jpg 1360w ,https://stitchedeth.github.io/ens/media/posts/16/responsive/Candy-Skull-original-2xl.jpg 1600w"  alt="" width="2582" height="2898"></figure>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Crude Things</title>
        <author>
            <name>CoreDevs</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://stitchedeth.github.io/ens/crude-things/"/>
        <id>https://stitchedeth.github.io/ens/crude-things/</id>

        <updated>2022-09-21T22:35:37-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://stitchedeth.github.io/ens/media/posts/15/Snake-Cat-Derivatives.gif" alt="" />
                    Her style is whimsical and erratic, and she often describes it as “art brut” (a term coined in the late 1940s by French Artist John Dubuffet, to whom her work is often compared). Lana Guerra (also known as Crude Things and Flutterbug) is a mixed-media&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://stitchedeth.github.io/ens/media/posts/15/Snake-Cat-Derivatives.gif" alt="" />
                <blockquote>
<h4 dir="ltr">Her style is whimsical and erratic, and she often  describes it as “art brut” (a term coined in the late 1940s by French Artist John Dubuffet, to  whom her work is often compared).</h4>
</blockquote>
<p dir="ltr">Lana Guerra (also known as <strong>Crude Things</strong> and <strong>Flutterbug</strong>) is a mixed-media artist whose  work—which includes paintings, puppets, photography, fashion, and stop-motion animation— has been exhibited extensively throughout the United States, Mexico, Canada, England, Turkey,  and France. She is also the owner and creator of Crude Things, an aesthetic brand with an ever growing cult following. Her fanciful wigs and costumes have been used for a variety of events,  such as Mardi Gras, Burning Man, and performances at Walt Disney World. </p>
<p dir="ltr">Her artistry draws inspiration from urban graffiti, primitive  masks, antique dolls, and decaying architecture, and explores the themes of childhood  innocence, voodoo, and imagination. Her process—which begins with pure and authentic  creative impulses—involves painting, drawing, erasing, re-working, layering, and using an  improvisational (stream-of-consciousness-like) technique.</p>
<p>Lana has various murals hidden throughout New Orleans, but No Money No Problem is  by far her most visible. Scrawled along the side of the old Frankie and Johnnie’s Furniture Store  building, its name is a throwback to the famously kitschy commercials that the now-defunct  New Orleans furniture store ran on local TV in the 1990s.</p>
<p>The artist may be contacted on instagram <a href="https://www.instagram.com/crudethings/">@crudethings</a></p>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>PREACHER</title>
        <author>
            <name>CoreDevs</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://stitchedeth.github.io/ens/preacher/"/>
        <id>https://stitchedeth.github.io/ens/preacher/</id>

        <updated>2022-09-21T22:38:00-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://stitchedeth.github.io/ens/media/posts/9/Preachers-Skull-Derivatives.gif" alt="" />
                    The artist known only as PREACHER is most prolific in his hometown of New Orleans, where he is known for his widespread wheat-pasting campaigns. Beyond street art, PREACHER also practices canvas-based fine art in a contemporary folk/street art style and incorporates many advertising themes and&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://stitchedeth.github.io/ens/media/posts/9/Preachers-Skull-Derivatives.gif" alt="" />
                <figure class="align-center"><img loading="lazy"  style="padding-top: 14vh;" src="https://stitchedeth.github.io/ens/media/posts/9/Preacher-Logo-white-on-transparent-background.png" sizes="100vw" srcset="https://stitchedeth.github.io/ens/media/posts/9/responsive/Preacher-Logo-white-on-transparent-background-xs.png 300w ,https://stitchedeth.github.io/ens/media/posts/9/responsive/Preacher-Logo-white-on-transparent-background-sm.png 480w ,https://stitchedeth.github.io/ens/media/posts/9/responsive/Preacher-Logo-white-on-transparent-background-md.png 768w ,https://stitchedeth.github.io/ens/media/posts/9/responsive/Preacher-Logo-white-on-transparent-background-lg.png 1024w ,https://stitchedeth.github.io/ens/media/posts/9/responsive/Preacher-Logo-white-on-transparent-background-xl.png 1360w ,https://stitchedeth.github.io/ens/media/posts/9/responsive/Preacher-Logo-white-on-transparent-background-2xl.png 1600w"  alt="" width="300" height="73"></figure>
<p>The artist known only as PREACHER is most prolific in his hometown of New Orleans, where he is known for his widespread wheat-pasting campaigns.</p>
<p>Beyond street art, PREACHER also practices canvas-based fine art in a contemporary folk/street art style and incorporates many advertising themes and techniques into his public works. The medium of choice for this muralist is wheat paste. For gallery-based work, mixed media and acrylic/aerosol are commonly used. </p>
<p>Known to use several types of paper (from wax blueprints, vintage music sheets, WWI journal entries, etc.) in his works, PREACHER experiments with the concepts of familiarity through realistic portraits and characters in combination with text. Though based in the “bible-belt” of the Southeast, PREACHER's plethora of work is not religiously charged. A visual dialogue is created in most of his works, drawing from themes of economics and commonly accompanied with aggressive sticker, moniker, and wheat pasting techniques.</p>
<p class="align-left">From the artist: </p>
<blockquote>
<div class="align-right" dir="auto">I have always had an issue with writing my name on things. The public domain is where I am most free to express myself. My thoughts are unconfined. My movements unrestricted. My work is designed top evoke feeling in the viewer. It is designed to breathe power and self-being into the viewers.</div>
<div dir="auto"> </div>
<div class="align-right" dir="auto">You can either find me painting in the field or in the privacy of my</div>
<div class="align-right" dir="auto">home, painting on canvas. Although texture rarely varies, canvas</div>
<div class="align-right" dir="auto">provides a platform for permanent and semi permanent work; not just temporary.</div>
<div dir="auto"> </div>
<div class="align-right" dir="auto">My current self-exploration has mainly been composed of acrylic paint, usually limited to black and white.  Aerosol, however, has been the backbone to my work for years. The combination of the two has allowed me to revisit my past and cross compare it with the present.</div>
</blockquote>
<p>The artist may be contacted on Instagram <a href="https://www.instagram.com/preacherart/">@preacherart</a></p>
<figure class="post__image align-center"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://stitchedeth.github.io/ens/media/posts/9/Preacher-Logo-black-on-transparent-background.png" sizes="100vw" srcset="https://stitchedeth.github.io/ens/media/posts/9/responsive/Preacher-Logo-black-on-transparent-background-xs.png 300w ,https://stitchedeth.github.io/ens/media/posts/9/responsive/Preacher-Logo-black-on-transparent-background-sm.png 480w ,https://stitchedeth.github.io/ens/media/posts/9/responsive/Preacher-Logo-black-on-transparent-background-md.png 768w ,https://stitchedeth.github.io/ens/media/posts/9/responsive/Preacher-Logo-black-on-transparent-background-lg.png 1024w ,https://stitchedeth.github.io/ens/media/posts/9/responsive/Preacher-Logo-black-on-transparent-background-xl.png 1360w ,https://stitchedeth.github.io/ens/media/posts/9/responsive/Preacher-Logo-black-on-transparent-background-2xl.png 1600w"  alt="" width="1105" height="268"></figure>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Decentralizing Fashion: NFTs for Copyright</title>
        <author>
            <name>CoreDevs</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://stitchedeth.github.io/ens/adore/"/>
        <id>https://stitchedeth.github.io/ens/adore/</id>

        <updated>2022-09-21T23:15:00-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://stitchedeth.github.io/ens/media/posts/10/Wide-Catalog-14.jpg" alt="" />
                    The stitched.eth ecosystem brings real-world utility to NFTs by embedding them with legally-enforceable intellectual property - worldwide, exclusive copyright interests Join Our Discord Enabling collectors, manufacturers and web3 users to trustlessly and equitably invest in artists ...without securitization, negotiation or government interference Our NFTs solve&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://stitchedeth.github.io/ens/media/posts/10/Wide-Catalog-14.jpg" alt="" />
                <div class="subtitle">
<h6 class="align-center">The stitched.eth ecosystem <span style="font-weight: 400;">brings real-world utility to NFTs by embedding them with legally-enforceable intellectual property - worldwide, <em>exclusive</em> copyright interests</span></h6>
<div class="btn"><a href="https://discord.gg/EtUXP9gncC">Join Our Discord</a></div>
</div>
<h3 class="align-center"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Enabling collectors, manufacturers and web3 users to trustlessly and </span>equitably invest in artists<span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></h3>
<h3 class="align-center"><span style="font-weight: 400;">...without securitization, negotiation or government interference</span></h3>
<div class="intro"><img loading="lazy" src="https://stitchedeth.github.io/ens/media/posts/10/Wide-Catalog-16.jpg" sizes="100vw" srcset="https://stitchedeth.github.io/ens/media/posts/10/responsive/Wide-Catalog-16-xs.jpg 300w ,https://stitchedeth.github.io/ens/media/posts/10/responsive/Wide-Catalog-16-sm.jpg 480w ,https://stitchedeth.github.io/ens/media/posts/10/responsive/Wide-Catalog-16-md.jpg 768w ,https://stitchedeth.github.io/ens/media/posts/10/responsive/Wide-Catalog-16-lg.jpg 1024w ,https://stitchedeth.github.io/ens/media/posts/10/responsive/Wide-Catalog-16-xl.jpg 1360w ,https://stitchedeth.github.io/ens/media/posts/10/responsive/Wide-Catalog-16-2xl.jpg 1600w"  alt="" width="1670" height="1257">
<div class="intro-text">
<h4 style="color: #000;">Our NFTs <strong>solve real-world problems</strong>.</h4>
<p> </p>
<p style="font-size: .8em; color: #000;">NFTs have gotten a bad rap: "Why buy jpgs?" - the world. Unfortunately, most NFT projects don't even attempt to solve real-world problems. <strong>stitched.eth does.</strong> </p>
</div>
</div>
<h2 style="text-align: center;"><a id="projectsummary"></a><strong>Realigning Incentives &amp; Redefining Markets</strong></h2>
<h6 style="font-weight: 300; text-align: center;">The <em>stitched.eth</em> ecosystem aims to solve a host of problems for several different groups of people:</h6>
<h6 style="font-weight: 300; text-align: center;">(1) artists,</h6>
<h6 style="font-weight: 300; text-align: center;">(2) clothing manufacturers,</h6>
<h6 style="font-weight: 300; text-align: center;">(3) art collectors/patrons, and</h6>
<h6 style="font-weight: 300; text-align: center;">(4) people who wear clothes 😁</h6>
<h6 style="font-weight: 300; text-align: center;">The ecosystem does this by realigning incentives, creating a new financial <em>interdependency</em>, and enhancing transparency. In the process, we enable crypto enthusiasts and NFT collectors to become decentralized clothing manufactuers and trade in legally-enforceable copyrights - an asset class that will inevitably bring new capital to traditional markets.</h6>
<div class="intro"><img loading="lazy" src="https://stitchedeth.github.io/ens/media/posts/10/Wide-Catalog-18.jpg" sizes="100vw" srcset="https://stitchedeth.github.io/ens/media/posts/10/responsive/Wide-Catalog-18-xs.jpg 300w ,https://stitchedeth.github.io/ens/media/posts/10/responsive/Wide-Catalog-18-sm.jpg 480w ,https://stitchedeth.github.io/ens/media/posts/10/responsive/Wide-Catalog-18-md.jpg 768w ,https://stitchedeth.github.io/ens/media/posts/10/responsive/Wide-Catalog-18-lg.jpg 1024w ,https://stitchedeth.github.io/ens/media/posts/10/responsive/Wide-Catalog-18-xl.jpg 1360w ,https://stitchedeth.github.io/ens/media/posts/10/responsive/Wide-Catalog-18-2xl.jpg 1600w"  alt="" width="1900" height="1498">
<div class="intro-text-right">
<ul style="list-style-type: none;">
<li>
<h5 style="margin-top: 3%;"><a href="#artists">What <i>stitched.eth</i> does for Artists</a></h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5 style="margin-top: 11%;"><a href="#patrons">What <i>stitched.eth</i> does for Collectors &amp; Patrons</a></h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5 style="margin-top: 11%;"><a href="#industry">What <i>stitched.eth</i> does for Clothing Manufacturers</a></h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5 style="margin-top: 11%;"><a href="#consumers">What <i>stitched.eth</i> does for everyone</a></h5>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<h2 class="align-center">Project Overview</h2>
<p>The <em>stitched.eth</em> project brings real-world utility to the blockchain by (1) embedding exclusive, legally-enforceable intellectual property interests (specifically, exclusive copyright interests) into NFTs and (2) creating an ecosystem wherein anyone with a crypto wallet can trustlessly trade in this real-world intellectual property and even use their copyright - not just sit on it - by manufacturing physical clothing and art with blockchain provenance, thereby creating limited-edition collectible fashions from real-world artists that may or may not be otherwise participating in the blockchain world</p>
<h6 class="align-center">This enables collectors, manufacturers and web3 users to trustlessly and equitably <strong>invest in artists</strong>.</h6>
<h2><strong><a id="artists"></a>What <i>stitched.eth</i> does for Artists</strong></h2>
<p>There are serious problems inherent in the traditional contemporary art ecosystem.</p>
<p>Artists have traditionally relied on some combination of private collectors, patrons, non-profits (like museums) or state-sponsored entities (such as municipalities or other government entities) to raise money for projects and to make a living. This creates an inherent power imbalance because artists rely on powerful institutions or wealthy individuals for financial support. Artists can get exploited, and artists themselves may feel pressure to compromise their vision.</p>
<p>Artists also often spend their time negotiating gallery contracts, sales and marketing or else applying to governments or institutions for public funding. This is not the best use of an artist's time. </p>
<p class="p1"><i>stitched.eth </i>was founded by a group of art collectors who were hungry for a different kind of contemporary art ecosystem. </p>
<h6>The Problems that <em>stitched.eth</em> Solves</h6>
<ul>
<li><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Problem #1.</span> The traditional dynamic does not provide much financial incentive for your collectors and patrons to invest in you or your work. Right now, galleries are the typical gatekeepers who do this kind of work. Galleries do not always make the best gatekeepers... If you're an artist, your most serious collectors and supporters want to invest in you, but the only mechanism to do this is by purchasing and displaying your art at whatever particular private location on earth they chose to place it.<br>
<ul>
<li><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Why is this a problem?</span> This antiquated ecosystem does not create any kind of real financial incentive for collectors to invest their capital into marketing the artist. Instead of investing money in the artist, they are incentivized only to <strong>buy</strong> the artwork and <strong>hold</strong> it. There is no financial incentive for a collector to give the artist money for promotion because the artist is more than happy to sell art in exchange for money. And that's the customary exchange - art for money. </li>
<li>So the collector will just continue acquiring more art, and the artist is therefore relegated to producing more and more art.</li>
<li>The financial incentive for the artist is produce art that the collectors want to buy - not necessarily art that the artist wants to produce.</li>
<li>Some people will buy because they appreciate the work, some people who are speculators might buy work hoping the value goes up. They are similarly incentivized to buy and hold, and acquire more and more artwork. Cynically, this type of collector often sees a major profit only after the artist's death.</li>
<li>And sadly, in any case, the artist only makes money at the time of the initial sale. </li>
<li>Most original art is purchased, hung on a wall in some private residence or put in storage. The collector doesn’t benefit from that, and neither does the artist. This does a disservice to both the artist and the collector. Taking away the public's ability to view the work limits the reach of the work, and this hinders both the artist's means to communicate and the public's appreciation for the message. </li>
<li>With the financial incentives the way they currently are, artists are in a position to be exploited. Artists do not have have an equitable negotiating position. Even if collectors want to support the artists, the financial incentives being the way they are result in the world we all know - collectors buy and hoard art, squirreling it away somewhere. And if the artist wants to expand their collector base, they often have to reduce their prices, give art away or compromise their production method.</li>
<li>Collectors are not incentivized to spend as much money on art as other traditional investments because there is no available cash flow from owning the art itself and conveyance of the art gives no additional rights. This depresses the amount of money people are willing to pay for art.</li>
<li><strong style="font-family: var(--editor-font-family); font-size: inherit;">It doesn't have to be this way. </strong><span style="color: var(--text-primary-color); font-family: var(--editor-font-family); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);"> Aligning financial incentives between artists and collectors changes the game. Artists can benefit from their collectors in a way that hasn't yet been done - artists can get the benefit of direct investment without having to trade the physical art itself. </span></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Problem #2</span>. Some types of art aren’t really “collectible” - for instance, poetry and street art. You can buy a book or a photograph of a poem or street art, but that isn’t really the official copy or limited edition. And there's no telling how many other similar copies are out there.
<ul>
<li>Collectibles are most valuable when they are <strong>scarce</strong>. <strong>Provable scarcity</strong> increases the value, and so does <strong>provable authenticity</strong>. In the traditional, antiquated, art world, the classic example of the attempt to create provable scarcity is through numbered prints. We all know the problem with numbered prints - how do you know that the artist (or copyright holder) isn't going to create additional series of numbered prints.</li>
<li>When you buy a numbered print, you are <em>trusting</em> the artist or copyright holder to act honestly.</li>
<li>And prints don't work very well for poetry and street art. Why? Well who knows, but all you have to do is reflect on your own experience - how many people do you know that collect prints of poetry? This problem might actually explain why poetry as an art form has been on the decline. </li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Problem #3.</span> If you’re in public and look around right now, you’ll see a lot of people wearing clothes that advertise only the clothing manufacturer itself (if anything at all). That’s a <span style="text-decoration: underline;">huge</span> missed opportunity to advertise amazing artists. Those artists are the culture-bearers who are spreading world-changing ideas, sharing beauty and improving the world around us. Why is it that we have become so comfortable using that advertising space for giant brands or throwing it away all together instead of using it to spread world-changing messages? </li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Problem #4</span>. The resale market for contemporary artists is so small as to be virtually nonexistent. Part of the reason is that provenance is expensive and time-consuming. It’s also because collectors don’t have a whole lot of financial incentives to spend real money promoting their artists (see Problem #1). </li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Problem #5</span>. Furthermore, for many artists, it can be prohibitively expensive or time-consuming to create a recurring revenue model where the artist can have a little bit financial breathing room. Printing can be expensive and requires marketing time and expense or gallery markups.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Problem #6</span>. Pricing art for sale to collectors and patrons is challenging as well. Artists typically need to make sure that original art is priced high enough to cover their costs and living expenses, but artists also don't want to limit their art to only collectors who have lots of money.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Problem #7</span>. Using apparel as a medium creates a mechanism to spread the artwork to the public at scale, but it is typically cost-prohibitive for artists because of the high minimum order quantities required to appreciate a reasonable margin and the complicated copyright-brokering process. The powerful institutional clothing brands have limited incentive to work with artists they don't "own" and extract a significant amount of value away from the artists, and sometimes even creative control.</li>
</ul>
<h6><strong><a href="#solutions">How does <em>stitched.eth</em> solve these problems?</a></strong></h6>
<h6><a href="../../../../../../about#new-artists">&gt;&gt;How artists are chosen</a></h6>
<h2><strong><a id="patrons"></a>What <i>stitched.eth</i> does for Collectors &amp; Patrons</strong></h2>
<p><em>stitched.eth</em> was actually founded by a group of art collectors who were hungry for a different kind of contemporary art ecosystem. In the traditional contemporary art ecosystem, art collectors typically "just" buy art. If an artist wants our support, we ask what they have for sale, and then we can buy it or not. That's how artists make money, and that's how it's always been. But there are serious problems inherent in that traditional ecosystem.</p>
<h6>The Problems that <em>stitched.eth</em> Solves</h6>
<ul>
<li><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Problem #1.</span> As an art collector, if you want to invest in art or support an artist, you buy artwork and hold it and maybe display it. Typically, you'll display the art in your home or other private space, or perhaps it ends up in storage. We all want museums to show off our work, but how often does that really happen - and how often do museums keep their holdings in storage out of public view. This "buy and hide and hold" model doesn't benefit you as a collector or the artist except for a one-time payment of money. 
<ul>
<li><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Why is this a problem?</span> As a collector, you want people to see the art, and so does the artist. In fact, the art becomes more valuable as more people are inspired by it. So you have a financial incentive to get people to see your art, but in the traditional ecosystem, this could only be done by inviting people to where you have it displayed or loaning it to other people. </li>
<li>Also, as a practical matter, there's only so much wall space any of us have. Eventually, if you want to continue supporting an artist, and the only means you have is to buy art, you're going to be giving the art away or hiding it. There's little financial motivation in buying art just to give it away, which perhaps isn't a problem for you - but it is for the artist. And buying art to put it in storage is not good for anyone in this ecosystem.</li>
<li>Further, there's no direct, recognizable economic benefit to investing into the artist beyond purchasing their art. Throughout history, we have just accepted this as the "way it is" - that collectors could become patrons, but only at their own expense and for the benefit of artists (which also creates a problematic power dynamic).</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Problem #2</span>. To realize a financial return on your investment in artwork, your only option under the traditional ecosystem is to sell the art. Well, that's a problem because you probably really like your art and don't want to part with it. Wouldn't it be great if you could have your cake and eat it too by keeping your art and still realizing some capital appreciation? Sure, you probably didn't get into art collecting to make money - but think about it this way - if you <em>could </em>potentially make money by collecting great art, how much more money would you spend on it in support of the artist? Also, how much more time, capital and energy would you put into promoting the art? </li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Problem #3</span>. Some types of art aren’t really “collectible” - for instance, poetry and street art. You can buy a book or a photograph of a poem or street art, but that isn’t really the official copy or limited edition. And there's no telling how many other similar copies are out there.
<ul>
<li>Collectibles are most valuable when they are <strong>scarce</strong>. <strong>Provable scarcity</strong> increases the value, and so does <strong>provable authenticity</strong>. In the traditional, antiquated, art world, the classic example of the attempt to create provable scarcity is through numbered prints. We all know the problem with numbered prints - how do you know that the artist (or copyright holder) isn't going to create additional series of numbered prints.</li>
<li>When you buy a numbered print, you are <em>trusting</em> the artist or copyright holder to act honestly.</li>
<li>And prints don't work very well for poetry and street art. Why? Well who knows, but all you have to do is reflect on your own experience - how many people do you know that collect prints of poetry? This problem might actually explain why poetry as an art form has been on the decline. </li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Problem #4.</span> If you’re in public and look around right now, you’ll see a lot of people wearing clothes that advertise only the clothing manufacturer itself (if anything at all). That’s a <span style="text-decoration: underline;">huge</span> missed opportunity to advertise amazing artists. Those artists are the culture-bearers who are spreading world-changing ideas, sharing beauty and improving the world around us. Why is it that we have become so comfortable using that advertising space for giant brands or throwing it away all together instead of using it to spread world-changing messages? </li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Problem #5</span>. Let's say the artist that you believed in becomes famous and widely collected, and now you do want to realize a financial gain by selling the work you purchased - selling it is not easy. As everyone knows, art resale markets are dominated by auction houses that only want to deal with an exclusive subset of well-known artists. It's often very difficult to resell outside of this context and nearly impossible to authenticate art that you might want to sell. Part of the reason for this is that provenance is expensive and time-consuming. It’s also because collectors don’t have a whole lot of financial incentives to spend real money promoting their artists (see Problem #1).</li>
</ul>
<h6><strong><a href="#solutions">How does <em>stitched.eth</em> solve these problems?</a></strong></h6>
<h2><strong><a id="solutions"></a>Problems Solved ✔️</strong></h2>
<p><em>stitched.eth</em> empowers both artists and collectors through web3 by enabling collectors to equitably <strong>invest</strong> in artists. <em>stitched.eth</em> embeds tradable, exclusive, but limited, copyright interests of artwork from artists that collectors already (or want to) collect into NFTs that can be used to manufacture clothing incorporating the artwork (we call these "Design NFTs"). Artists don't have to sell their work to get money; instead, collectors have an incentive to spend their money directly promoting and supporting artists and the artwork of their Design NFTs. This helps the artist get exposure and support without having to fund projects or sell their time and art.</p>
<p><em>stitched.eth</em> also registers each garment that is produced on the blockchain, providing a 100% transparent, public mechanism to verify both the <strong>authenticity</strong> and <strong>scarcity</strong> of garments.</p>
<p>When collectors buy one of these copyright-embedded NFTs, they are purchasing much more than a JPG - they get the actual, real-world, legally-enforceable intellectual property, and because it's an exclusive right, they are not reliant on us to enforce their copyright. The process of buying an NFT is just the same as buying any other NFT; all they have to do is use their crypto wallet. </p>
<p>This creates an ecosystem where incentives are aligned and there is an economic <em>interdependency </em>that economically benefits both the artists <em>and</em> patrons. Human nature being what it is, when it makes economic sense for people, people will be more willing to support artists than they would be if you rely solely on the kindness of their hearts. <em>stitched.eth</em> therefore incentivizes collectors to invest in artists in a way that has never happened before.</p>
<p>Art comes to life, not just through a sculpture, framed wall art, or a digital NFT, but here also through apparel - transforming artwork into utilitarian consumer products and artists into their own brands. Given the opportunity, consumers would rather be a walking billboard for the artists that they love than for the powerful, damaging brands that they are forced to choose among to clothe themselves. </p>
<p>When a collector buys a <em>stitched.eth</em> copyright-embedded NFT, the collector now owns a very small piece of the intellectual property of the artist. The copyright itself has value that is dependent in no small part on the investment capital, resources, and skill that the owner of the NFT decides to invest in the promotion of the art and the artist. The NFT holder/collector now has an independent financial interest in promoting the artist and that particular artwork because the NFT holder/collector can <span style="text-decoration: underline;">use the rights</span> without giving up the artwork. The NFT holder/collector can manufacture clothing, promote that clothing, sell the clothing, and still retain ownership of the intellectual property. And now that thousands of people are walking around wearing their favorite artist on their back, the value of that NFT (and even the apparel itself!) increases.</p>
<p>Additionally, the restrictions placed on the copyright allow the artist to keep control over their designs and artwork. The main restrictions are that (1) the only permitted uses are for fashion articles - the artist retains all other uses, (2) all uses of the artwork must be approved by the artist, (3) only a fixed amount - the exact number dependent on the NFT itself - of the artwork can be reproduced each year. Accordingly, artists can maximize the value of their work by capturing recurring revenue through a profit-sharing model, or artists can negotiate any kind of deal that they want with the collector.</p>
<p>So what happens if a deal isn't able to be negotiated? Well, nothing is produced. That does not benefit either the artist or the NFT holder/collector. So both parties have an equal incentive to negotiate and compromise in good faith - hence, equity is inherent in the <em>stitched.eth</em> ecosystem.</p>
<p>In addition, <em>stitched.eth</em> can guarantee the authenticity of physical garments through the blockchain because each time a garment is made, it can be registered on the blockchain as its own "Garment NFT" and delivered to the person who purchased the product. The Garment NFT is registered on our own decentralized, public registry. That way, everyone can trustlessly and transparently know whether a particular is authentic.</p>
<p>Finally, provable scarcity is achieved through the same Garment NFT registry. Each time the artwork is incorporated into a garment, the garment is noted on the registry for the applicable Design NFT.  These Garment NFTs and combined with the public registry create a digital certificate of authenticity that cannot be replicated. </p>
<p>For artists in our <em>stitched.eth</em> ecosystem, your collectors are financially incentivized to  invest in bringing your art to the streets, and you can get paid for it every time this happens. You can get more, and more deeply-connected collectors, collectors can earn a real return on their investment in your art, and consumers get accessible art that they can showcase on their bodies every day.</p>
<h6><a href="https://stitchedeth.github.io/ens/about/">Take a deeper dive</a></h6>
<h2><strong><a id="industry"></a>What <i>stitched.eth</i> does for Clothing Manufacturers</strong></h2>
<p>In the current antiquated, marketplace, clothing manufacturers are leaving money on the table. There are innumerable artists that are producing incredible, high-powered works that are currently restrained to wallspace. Many of these artists have devoted followers and patrons who would happily line up behind a brand that invests in their artist. </p>
<p>But the transaction costs of incorporating art from these artists has been high. Additionally, collectors have not necessarily seen wearable art as collectible because it lacked <strong>provable scaracity</strong>, or else it was difficult to tell whether it was <strong>authentic</strong>.</p>
<p>In solving these problems, <em>stitched.eth</em> empowers manufacturers to capture the value proposition of collectibles and activate the powerful loyalties of art collectors and enthusiasts, increasing a consumer's willingness to pay, and ultimately improving margins. </p>
<p><strong>How does <em>stitched.eth</em> solve these problems?</strong></p>
<p>By embedding artist copyrights into NFTs, manufacturers can acquire high-value exclusive copyright licenses in a trustless and frictionless public marketplace. In the <em>stitched.eth</em> ecosystem, and all you have to do is purchase the copyright-embedded Design NFT in order to get an copyright license - and it's a license that comes with no obligations to use it within any specific timeframe and is freely tradeable at any time in the future on any standard NFT marketplace. </p>
<p>Each time the artwork is used on a garment, the use is registered on the blockchain on our own decentralized, public registry. That way, everyone can trustlessly and transparently prove the scarcity of any particular artwork.</p>
<p>In addition, <em>stitched.eth</em> can guarantee the authenticity of physical garments through the blockchain through the production of garment-level "Garment NFTs." These NFTs can be delivered to the person who purchased the specific garment and will be registered on our public, decentralized registry as well. These Garment NFTs and combined with the public registry create a digital certificate of authenticity that cannot be replicated. And all of this is done transparently so that anyone in the world can recognize and prove that any particular garment is the "real deal."</p>
<h2><strong><a id="consumers"></a>What <i>stitched.eth</i> does for <span style="text-decoration: underline;">everyone</span></strong></h2>
<p>We all wear clothes. <strong>And right now we're doing it all wrong.</strong></p>
<p>We buy art from talented artists and hang it up in private places, while every day we walk around promoting clothing brands (that really don't need free advertising) on our bodies.</p>
<p>We love art, but we cut the artists right out of the best advertising opportunity imaginable. Why is it that the best contemporary artists are not featured by the best clothing brands?</p>
<p><em>stitched.eth</em> uses web3 technology to create an ecosystem where clothing brands, retailers, and art collectors can trade copyright-protected artworks. The <em>stitched.eth </em>ecosystem guarantees real equity for artists, and for everyone else out there - it incentivizes manufacturers to produce clothing featuring your favorite artists so that you can wear your <em>artist as a brand</em>.</p>
<p>In the current, traiditonal ecosystem, clothes featuring art were seen as commodity - they were not collecitble because they were not scarce or easily proved to be authentic. </p>
<p>In the <em>stitched.eth</em> ecosystem, each time artwork is used on a garment, the garment is registered on the blockchain on our own decentralized, public registry. That way, everyone can trustlessly and transparently prove the scarcity of any particular artwork.</p>
<p>In addition, <em>stitched.eth</em> can guarantee the authenticity of physical garments through the blockchain through the production of garment-level "Garment NFTs." These NFTs can be delivered to the person who purchased the specific garment and will be registered on our public, decentralized registry as well. These Garment NFTs and combined with the public registry create a digital certificate of authenticity that cannot be replicated. And all of this is done transparently so that anyone in the world can recognize and prove that any particular garment is the "real deal."</p>
<h6><a href="https://stitchedeth.github.io/ens/about/">Take a deeper dive</a></h6>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
